

07946 538 191 me@barryhalper.com www.barryhalper.com www.github.com/barryhalper ♀



PROFILE

I am a highly motivated full-stack web developer with over twenty years experience delivering market-leading business-to-business brands. I have extensive knowledge in web development, database architecture, web design, SEO, and server/domain management. As a technical lead, I have experience in team building, managing developers, determining project requirements, liaising with both internal and external clients to deliver projects that increase profits, and drive efficiency.



EXPERIENCE

Hemming Group Ltd 2000-2020 WEB DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

Fulfilling the roles of application architect, technical lead and DBA I was responsibe for creating and managing a range business applications, CRMs, CMS and REST APIs for the publishing and events business.

I implemented innovations in data storage, ecommce, publising and customer fullfilment systems. I upgraded the development platform (CF to .NET) and help stear the business towards iterative development using the latest web technologies/frameworks, UX standards and SEO best practices. As a manger I helped created the Hemming web team of three developers, a designer and a project manager.

SENIOR DEVELOPER 2005-2008

Responsible for hiring and managing a team of developers to delivery web solutions for the publishing business.e,g the development of a business wide CMS, used to publish localgov content (and its sister titles) on a in single paltform. I successfullly deilvered directory and data sales web applications for the local government sector by generating significate revenues. I implemented code standards, naming convetions and frameworks (fusebox)



EDUCATION

M.A. Literature, Culture & ModernityUniversity of London 1996-1998

B.A.(hons) English Literature & History (2:1) Manchester University 1990 -1993

Greenhill College, Harrow

3 A Levels & 6 GCE'S (including maths & english) 1987-1990



SKILLS

ASP NET Framework/Core (C#) MVC, Web Forms, REST API, Entity Framework, LinqToSQL, Coldfusion Enterprise Server, Verity, Fusebox, CFscript, Javascript ES5 & ES6, JQuery, JSON, Babel, HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap, XML, XSD, MS IIS, MS Windows Server, DNS management, MSSQL Servevr, MS SQL Management Studio, T-SQL, MongoDB, Compass, MS Visual Studio, Dreamweaver, LinqPad, Eclipse, Subversion, Tortoise SVN, Git Hub, Web services Restful APIs, SOAP, Postman, CORS, Photoshop, MS Access applications (VB), ecommerce, Stripe, Worldpay

for the team. Provisioned hosting company.

WEB DEVELOPER 2005-2003

Created many websites for the enitre publising business inclduing "Lingerie Buyer" and "Company clothing" I created intranet applications for email marketing and subscription fullfillment using Coldfusion and Sql Server. I introduced ecommce to the business through Worldpay intergration and implmented Gooogle Analytics for all sites.

EDITOR 2003-2002

Wrote a newsletter on local government tenders, reveiws and features in Company Clothing magazine and was the editor for Muncipal Yeearbook Procurement guide

RESEARCH & DEVELOPMENT ASSITANT 2000-2001

Conversion of filemaker databases into MS Access. Created database applications for the data entry teams using SQL, VB. Updgraded Access databases to MS SQL server for online use. Run data applications that exported content out of SQL into QuarkXpress for print publishing. Created online HTML forms.

Company Clothing 1998-2000 RESEARCH ASSISTANT

I used my of knowloade of research garnered from my MA to create content and data for Company clothing magazine and it's trade show. I updated the subscription databases using FileMaker. I created a successful fax /email news service project for tenders and spearheading developments for the business in IT and editorial. This company was bought by the Hemming Group in 2000 I was one of the few to kept on.

Hammicks Legal Bookshop 1994-1995

HEAD OF SUBSCRIPTIONS

I ran the subscriptions/mail order department responsible for postal orders for the Inns of court and legal services in Central London.

Blackwells bookshop 1993-1994

BOOKSELLER

I ran the fiction and history sections in this

Freelance Web Developer 1998-2005

While at the Hemming Group I worked freelance, building websites for local businesses such an estate agent, two architectural firms as well developing a site with artists from the Royal academy a project the successfully recieved funding from the Arts Council



TRAINING COURSES

MS Access and SQL 2001
Introduction to Coldfusion 2001
Dreamweaver Ultradev 2001
MS Project 2003
Advanced Coldfusion 2004
Search Engine Optimisation Best Pratice 2004
Time Management 2005
The Newly appointed manager 2006
ASP.NET Programming in C# 2009
Angular JS 2017



HOBBIES

I am an avid reader, film buff and member if the BFI

I love all types of music, play rhythm guitar and attend gigs as often as possible
I am passionate about good food and regularly cook for friends and family
I keep fit by regular walking and swimming
I am fascinated by history both modern and ancient
I like to discover new places and have travelled widely

I speak a little Japanese

٥٥

RECENT PROJECTS

Municipal Yearbook: Public Spend https://www.mybpublicspend.com

A B2B application that aggregates spending data published by UK Councils over the last 5 years, presenting it to subscribers in a suite of custom-built web reporting tools The project consists of a subscriber-only web application and a CMS/CRM that allows the data team to upload data from XML and CSV artefacts and manage user fulfilment. Built on the Microsoft stack of SQL Server 2016, ASP.NET framework, MVC and Entity Framework, and utilising test-driven development, the application includes various data warehousing, indexing and caching techniques as well as JQuery and a Rest API to optimise the performance of a data set of over 48,000,000 rows. This ensures the complex algorithms that aggregate data can render efficiently a range of customer-defined, reports, charts, and datasets. As well as building all the database architecture and applications I also created the UX using good practice web design based on industry standards of HTML5 and Twitter Bootstrap, Javascript and helped in the creation of the marketing site by the front end team.

Hemming Publishing CMS

This directory is a market leader in online repositories providing the most current information on all UK local government officers and elected officials. For this project, I created and managed a subscription-based web application, an editorial CRM and a client-facing RESTFUL API. The SQL database and .NET web application features payment based access and entitlement (using Stripe), order progression and subscription fulfilment as well as complex data analysis and reporting. The web application provides an intuitive user interface to help users access the information quickly and efficiently and has a customisable dashboard so subscribers can target key information to help make smart business decisions. To this end, I employed a team of designers and third party testers to deliver this project on time and on budget. I also worked closely with the editorial departments to create a CRM to manage the whole cycle of data collation and entry. I also created and ran the process that enabled editorial to export the data from SQL to Indesign for physical publication.

Localgov https://www.localgov.co.uk

The UK's largest dedicated local government news website. I led a team of contractors to deliver this project using Coldfusion, Javascript, Ajax and MS SQL server. The product was successfully launched in January 2006, winning in its first few months a special recommendation industry award. The project includes a custom-built CMS Full-Text searches, a REST API and integrations tools with third-party providers. A good example of iterative development across the full stack, I have redesigned and rebuilt this site using C# .Net web forms then NET.MVC and bootstrap 3 based on responsive design principles. The design template for the site has been reused for many other titles in the Hemming portfolio.

Municipal Yearbook https://www.municipalyearbook.co.uk/

This directory is a market leader in online repositories providing the most current information on all UK local government officers and elected officials. For this project, I created and managed a subscription-based web application, an editorial CRM and a client-facing RESTFUL API. The SQL database and .NET web application features payment based access and entitlement (using Stripe), order progression and subscription fulfilment as well as complex data analysis and reporting. The web application provides an intuitive user interface to help users access the information quickly and efficiently and has a customisable dashboard so subscribers can target key information to help make smart business decisions. To this end, I employed a team of designers and third party testers to deliver this project on time and on budget. I also worked closely with the editorial departments to create a CRM to manage the whole cycle of data collation and entry. I also created and ran the process that enabled editorial to export the data from SQL to Indesign for physical publication.